Helena Asfaw

Bilingual Customer Service Agent

SKILLS

Fluent in French and English with a working knowledge of Spanish.

Experienced working as a customer service agent and in administrative support positions.

Great organizational skills and attention to detail.

Work well as a team creating a favorable environment.

Ability to communicate effectively dealing with varying groups of people.

Comfortable taking leadership roles as necessary and working independently.

Ability to adapt quickly to changing situations.

Obtained Bachelor of Arts with Honors from York University.

EXPERIENCE

CAA Quebec, Montreal, QC - Bilingual Customer Service

OCT 2022 - JULY 2023

- Handle a high-volume of inbound and outbound calls in French and English to provide roadside assistance and member services to callers.
- Effectively utilize and navigate a variety of systems to access information necessary to provide optimal service.
- Provide technical assistance to customers with their online accounts.

Urgently Roadside Assistance, Montreal, QC - Bilingual Customer Service

OCT 2020 - DEC 2021

- Provided roadside assistance services to customers in a high call volume call-centre environment.
- Managed challenging customer service situations while maintaining a positive,
 empathetic, and consultative approach towards the customer during their time of need.
- Applied critical thinking and sound judgment to assess different situations to best support customers in their decision making process.

The Gangl Family, New York, NY - Babysitter

MAR 2017 - DEC 2017

- Cared for a 7 month old baby keeping track of feeding and nap times, cleaning her when necessary and keeping an eye on her to ensure her physical safety.
- Supported her development by taking her to story time for babies, the children's museum, the botanical gardens, playgrounds and by scheduling play dates.

The Three Jewels, New York, NY - Client Care

NOV 2016 - SEP 2017

- Worked as a front desk agent greeting and signing-in guests with MindBody Online Software.
- Managed bookstore and membership sales.
- Answered calls and addressed customers' questions and concerns.

Aon Hewitt, Toronto, ON - Bilingual Customer Service

SFP 2015 - APR 2016

- Worked in a call-centre environment in English and French assisting active and retired employees with adjusting and understanding their health care benefits.
- Carefully examined submitted documents to properly assess each case and provide accurate information to callers.
- Provided detailed instructions to callers based on their situations by using the extensive information repository that was at my disposal.

Equifax Canada, Toronto, ON - Bilingual Customer Service

DEC 2014 - SEP 2015

- Responsible for managing all aspects of customer service in French and English via phone and email.
- Worked in a call-centre environment responding to a high volume of customer inquiries of varying degrees of complexity.
- Responsible for educating members on how to read and understand credit bureau files as well as providing guidance on standardized procedures.

Dietitians of Canada, Toronto, ON - Customer Care & Administrative Assistant

FEB 2012 - DEC 2013

- Resolved 99% of French and English enquiries received through customer service within 72 hours, exceeding the set standards of 85% within 72 hours.
- Created standardized responses enhancing the knowledge repository of the customer service database to reduce response times.
- Trained newly hired colleagues and created reference documents for various programs to aid in the orientation process.

EDUCATION

York University, Toronto, ON - BA in Film Studies

JUN - 2010